<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2014-2018 Kitware, Inc. -->
<component type="desktop-application">
 <id>org.paraview.paraview</id>
 <metadata_license>CC-BY-4.0</metadata_license>
 <project_license>BSD</project_license>
 <name>ParaView</name>
 <summary>Data analysis and visualization</summary>
 <description>
  <p>
   ParaView is an open-source, multi-platform data analysis and visualization
   application. ParaView users can quickly build visualizations to analyze
   their data using qualitative and quantitative techniques. The data
   exploration can be done interactively in 3D or programmatically using
   ParaView’s batch processing capabilities.
  </p>
  <p>
   ParaView was developed to analyze extremely large datasets using distributed
   memory computing resources. It can be run on supercomputers to analyze
   datasets of exascale size as well as on laptops for smaller data.
  </p>
 </description>
 <categories>
  <category>Science</category>
 </categories>
 <screenshots>
  <screenshot type="default">
   <caption>Using ParaView to compare simulated and analytical results (Image courtesy of Sandia National Labs)</caption>
   <image width="902" height="677">http://www.paraview.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/full_AlegraVV.png</image>
  </screenshot>
  <screenshot>
   <caption>Global Seismic Wave Propagation Simulation (Contributors from ICES, The University of Texas at Austin: Carsten Burstedde, Omar Ghattas, James R. Martin, Georg Stadler, Lucas C. Wilcox Visualization at the Texas Advanced Computing Center, the University of Texas at Austin by Greg Abram)</caption>
   <image width="812" height="468">http://www.paraview.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/seismic.jpg</image>
  </screenshot>
  <screenshot>
   <caption>Polar Vortex Breakdown Simulation (Image courtesy of Sandia National Labs)</caption>
   <image width="940" height="661">http://www.paraview.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/full_PolarVortexBreakdown.png</image>
  </screenshot>
  <screenshot>
   <caption>Hydrodynamic simulations of quark-gluon plasma (Russell Taylor's Comp 715: Visualization in the Sciences class at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Author: Joo Hwi Lee and Zhigang (Alfred) Zhong Copyright: Data courtesy of Steffen Bass and Hannah Peterson, Duke Physics)</caption>
   <image width="875" height="700">http://www.paraview.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/full_hydrodynamic_simulation.png</image>
  </screenshot>
  <screenshot>
   <caption>Cross Wind Fire Simulation (Image courtesy of Sandia National Labs)</caption>
   <image width="902" height="609">http://www.paraview.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/0_full_Fire.png</image>
  </screenshot>
 </screenshots>
 <launchable type="desktop-id">org.paraview.ParaView.desktop</launchable>
 <url type="homepage">http://paraview.org/</url>
 <url type="bugtracker">https://gitlab.kitware.com/paraview/paraview/-/issues</url>
 <url type="faq">https://www.paraview.org/Wiki/ParaView:FAQ</url>
 <url type="help">https://www.paraview.org/documentation/</url>
 <update_contact>paraview+paraview-support@discourse.paraview.org</update_contact>
</component>
